

Michael Horvath

Backend Software Developer

12 December 1987

California

949-409-5713

michaelhorvath87@gmail.com

About me-

Originally from Kansas, Michael has lived in eight states and two countries. Michael enjoys climbing, running, playing guitar and anything that gets him outside. He's been writing software for about seven years now, but he's been exploring since the day he could walk perhaps even earlier.

Skill.

Python CSS VIM

Linux

Whiteboarding

Figuring it out

(*)[The skill scale is from 0 (Fundamental Awareness) to 6 (Expert).]

beliefs

Continual growth is key to enjoyment of life; challenge begets growth.

Passion is a must.

Software = Poetry + Math

education

2006-2011 B.A. cum laude University of Kansas

Psychology and Statistics

2002-2006 High school, 4.0 GPA Shawnee Mission East HS

Extras: Diving, Soccer, Choir, Science Olympics

awa rds

1997-2001 Math Olympics State Champion, Pennsylvania Assoc. of Private Schools

2005 Science Olympiad State Champion, Chemistry

CalTech Signature Award, Excellence in Science and Mathematics 2006

Heart and Soul Award, Lawrence Ultimate Frisbee League 2016

experience

February 2022Software Engineer

Maxar Technologies

- Back-end development in Sanic micro-service architecture system.

- Functional and unit testing in CI/CD system.

2021 - 2022 Lead Data Scientist Fluxergy

- Design, development, testing and release of real-time quantitative diagnostic algorithms for PCR and lateral flow tests.

- Study design, program evaluation, and data sampling for validation of human medical device algorithms.

- Designed, connected, and commodified business intelligence pipelines across departments.

2020 - 2021 Algorithms Engineer Fluxergy

- Redesigned primary image-based PCR analysis algorithm, through all phases of QMS software development lifecycle.

2018 - 2020 Software Engineer

Fluxergy

- Designed, developed, and maintained data-centric internal applications, run in docker-ized cloud environments.

- Managed entire softwared development lifecycle for internet-of-things (IOT) manufacturing shop floor system.

2017 - 2018 Software Engineer

Embrace Healthwear

Data preprocessing, pipelining and analysis of motion-sensor high-frequency

time-series data.

2015 - 2022 Personal Projects

of basic machine learning processes in Elixir.

- High frequency trading algorithm development and back-testing.

skills

2018-2022 Python, Django, Flask, Sanic, PHP, MySQL, Docker, LaTex, docker-

compose, Git, Cloud resources (Azure and AWS), Database desgin, Elasticsearch and Kibana, PowerBI, Javascript/HTML/CSS, CI/CD, Infrastruc-

2010-2020 Program evaluation, technical liaison, public speaking, regression analysis,

ANOVA, MANOVA, optimization, structural equation modeling, business intelligence.